¬ Localisation file for transition screen quotes
¬ Lines in brackets are not to be translated

{Quote_101}
"Point d’argent, point de suisse." ("No money, no Swiss.")
{Author_101}
French saying.

{Quote_102}
"God give us one hundred years of war... and not a single day of battle!"
{Author_102}
Famous phrase amongst the Landsknetchs.

{Quote_103}
"Ne frustra vixisse videar." ("I hope I did not live in vain.)"
{Author_103}
Tycho Brahe, Danish astronomer, on his deathbed.

{Quote_104}
"E pur si muove!" ("And yet it moves!")
{Author_104}
Italian saying attributed to Galileo Galilei.

{Quote_105}
"L'État, c'est moi." ("I am the state.")
{Author_105}
Louis XIV, King of France and Navarre, before the Parlement of Paris in 1655.

{Quote_106}
"Twice he opened his eyes, and then he closed them forever."
{Author_106}
Thomas de Longueville, on Turenne's death at the battle of Salzbach, 27 July 1675.

{Quote_107}
“Here I wish to die with the Italian gentlemen.”
{Author_107}
Francisco De Melo, upon reaching the Visconti Tercio to offer a last stand at Rocroi, 1643.

{Quote_108}
"The valour of the defeated is the glory of the victor."
{Author_108}
Ambrogio Spinola, on the surrender of the garrison of Breda.

{Quote_109}
"It is related that the Prince Condé slept soundly the night before the battle of Rocroi."
{Author_109}
Alessandro Manzoni, 'The Betrothed' - Chapter 2.

{Quote_110}
"War is the greatest plague that can afflict humanity, it destroys religion, it destroys states, it destroys families. Any scourge is preferable to it."
{Author_110}
Martin Luther.

{Quote_111}
"I am so deep into this lake of blood that to go back to where I started would be as difficult as reaching the other shore."
{Author_111}
William Shakespeare, 'Macbeth' - Act III, scene 4.

{Quote_112}
"Soldiers! Face to the enemy. Let's go and get killed."
{Author_112}
French colonel to his men at the battle of Borodino.

{Quote_113}
"I speak Spanish to God, Italian to women, French to men, and German to my horse."
{Author_113}
Charles V, Holy Roman Emperor and King of Spain.

{Quote_114}
"Nothing is so well known as the Siege of Malta."
{Author_114}
François-Marie Arouet, known as 'Voltaire'.

{Quote_115}
"If I win the battle, I promise you your liberty. If the day is yours, then God has given it to you."
{Author_115}
Ali Pasha, to the christian slaves manning the Ottoman galleys at the battle of Lepanto.

{Quote_116}
"Christ reigns in such a way that the Emperor who persecutes Luther for the Pope is forced to destroy the Pope for Luther."
{Author_116}
Martin Luther, upon hearing of the Sack of Rome(1527).

{Quote_117}
"I was the King of Sweden."
{Author_117}
Gustavus Adolphus at the battle of Lutzen(1632) - His last words. 

{Quote_118}
"For war you need three things: 1. Money. 2. Money. 3. Money."
{Author_118}
Raimondo Montecuccoli.

{Quote_119}
"Whether I rise very high or not, I am content because I climb alone!"
{Author_119}
Edmond Rostand, 'Cyrano de Bergerac' - Scene VIII.

{Quote_120}
"My brother Charles wants to act the Alexander, but he shall not find a Darius in me."
{Author_120}
Peter the Great, on Charles XII of Sweden.

{Quote_121}
"I have resolved never to start an unjust war but never to end a legitimate one except by defeating my enemies"
{Author_121}
Attributed by Voltaire to Charles XII of Sweden.

{Quote_122}
"The French foot remained in the best order I ever saw, till they were cut to pieces almost in rank and file."
{Author_122}
George Hamilton, 1st Earl of Orkney, at the battle of Blenheim(1704).

{Quote_123}
"It is hardly believable that a man who carries on his shoulders the burden of almost all the affairs of Europe should find as much time to read as though he had nothing else to do."
{Author_123}
Jean-Baptiste Rousseau, on Eugene of Savoy's impressive collection of books and art.
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++